[Music]
when james parkinson first described the
classical symptoms of the disease he
could hardly foresee the evolution of
our understanding over the next 200
years like
the role of nutrition
increasing parkinson's disease risk with
high dietary intakes of animal fat iron
mercury and dairy products whereas the
intake of antioxidants in a plant-based
dietary pattern may be protective
plant-based diets are known to preserve
body tissues from oxidative stress and
inflammation both hallmarks
of chronic degenerative diseases like
parkinson's
on the contrary animal-based foods
particularly rich in animal proteins and
saturated fats are correlated with the
promotion
of neurodegenerative diseases in
addition to some of the leading killers
like cancer heart disease diabetes etc
not all plants are necessarily good
though for example the potential
neurotoxicity of graviola
a fruit known as soursop
consumption of soursop can lower blood
pressure and uric acid levels but may
also cause an atypical form of
parkinson's disease
because the fruit contains neurotoxic
compounds and indeed population studies
do show a link between the
overconsumption of soursop with
neurodegenerative disease
yes those who follow a predominantly
plant-based diet may show the lowest
prevalence in incidence of parkinson's
disease but plant-based nutrition is not
just about reducing the risk but can
also be used to manage the disease
in my video treating parkinson's disease
with diet i discussed this case report
which a diet low in animal fat and
including both whole grains every day as
well as one to two cups of strawberries
a day
seem to be effective in reducing
symptoms of parkinson's disease but
there are like 20 000 edible plants out
there and only a limited number of them
have been studied for
anti-parkinson's activity
one plant that's got a lot of attention
is coffee which may exert a protective
effect against the development of
parkinson's disease and may even help
slow down the progression of the disease
based on studies like this that show the
parkinson's patients who drink coffee or
caffeinated tea appear to cut their risk
of dying prematurely in half
but correlation doesn't mean cause-ish
you don't know if caffeine really works
until you
put it to the test
caffeine for the treatment
of parkinson's disease a six-week
randomized placebo-controlled
double-blind study
the caffeine group was started out
approximately a cup of coffee's worth of
caffeine twice a day once in the morning
once after lunch and then increasing it
to two cups worth twice a day which
would be like four cups of black tea
twice a day or six cups of green and
a significant improvement in parkinson's
symptoms within three weeks compared to
placebo a cheap
safe simple treatment for parkinson's
though an important limitation was the
duration of the study caffeine has
what's called a
tachyphylactic property meaning its
effects tend to diminish over time with
repeated use at least when trying to
combat sleepiness
so it would be really nice to see the
study repeated over a longer time frame
but there was no such longer study
until five years later
randomizing parkinson's patients to
about two cups of coffee worth of
caffeine twice a day for not six weeks
but more than six months
and
no
benefit over placebo
rats
caffeine did not provide sustained
symptomatic benefit after all so
caffeine may have a short-term benefit
which quickly dissipates regardless
caffeine cannot be recommended as a
symptomatic therapy for parkinsonism
[Music]
you